uvu.edu 2018-10-16

# Privacy | Legal | Utah Valley University

## Purpose

Utah Valley University (“UVU”) has created this Privacy Statement to explain why UVU collects particular information and how UVU will protect your personal privacy when you visit UVU websites. In order to fully understand your rights UVU encourages you to read this Privacy Statement. By choosing to continue to use UVU websites, you agree to UVU’s collection and use of personal information and non-personal information as described in this Privacy Statement. UVU reserves the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time, and UVU encourages you to frequently check this page for any changes to this Privacy Statement. 

## Scope

This Privacy Statement applies to all UVU websites, domains, services, applications, and technology products, except that a privacy notice specific to another department or unit of UVU will supplement and may supersede this Privacy Statement. 

Please be aware of UVU’s GDPR Privacy Notice that supplements this Privacy Statement. The GDPR Privacy Notice applies generally to the provision of personal information by individuals in the European Economic Area. The GDPR Privacy Notice explains how UVU meets its obligations under the [European Union General Data Protection Regulation](http://data.consilium.europa.eu/doc/document/ST-5419-2016-INIT/en/pdf) with respect to such information. For details, please refer to the GDPR Privacy Notice. 

## Collection of Information

UVU collects information via UVU websites that falls into one of two categories: personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information is any information that personally identifies you or from which you could be identified. UVU collects personally identifiable information whenever you voluntarily submit it to UVU websites, including your name, email, mailing address, telephone number, plus your preferences regarding UVU services. 

Non-personally identifiable information is information that is not directly tied to a specific user, such as the number of people who visit UVU websites from various states. Unless you take steps to browse the Internet anonymously, or [opt-out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout), UVU, like most institutions and organizations on the Internet, tracks web browsing patterns to inform understanding of how UVU websites are being used. Generic information is collected through the use of “cookies,” which are text files placed on your computer, to evaluate usage patterns so that UVU can improve both content and distribution. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; however, doing so may prevent you from using the full functionality of all UVU websites. The generic information UVU collects is based on IP address, which is the location of a computer or network, and is not linked to your specific email address in any of the reports or other material compiled by UVU. UVU will not associate your IP address and web usage data with any other information held by UVU that can specifically identify you unless required to do so by law. 

## Use of Information

By providing information to UVU through its websites you acknowledge that, where permitted by federal or state law, UVU may use this information for the express purposes for which the information was provided, which may include to: 

  * Respond to your requests for information
  * Process applications for admission or employment
  * Process information for administrative purposes
  * Process orders for goods or services
  * Notify you of products or services
  * Improve online content and communications
  * Improve UVU services
  * Process information for purposes as may be detailed on UVU websites or mobile applications

## Sharing of Information

UVU works with many vendors and contractors who assist UVU with its day-to-day affairs. Information that you provide to UVU or which UVU automatically collects is used or shared with these organizations for the express purposes for which the information was collected or as otherwise expressed in this Privacy Statement. UVU vendors and contractors are only permitted to use personal information for the express purposes permitted in their agreements with UVU. Otherwise, personally identifiable information is not released to third parties unless permitted by applicable law, including in instances where the information needs to be disclosed to protect the safety and security of the UVU community or UVU property, or where UVU is legally compelled by law or judicial order. 

## Public Forums

UVU websites may provide chat rooms, forums, message boards, and news groups for their users. Any information that is disclosed in these areas may become public information and a user should therefore exercise caution when deciding to disclose one’s personal information in such places. Chat sessions and discussion forums may be logged. 

## Protecting Children’s Privacy

If a user of UVU websites is under the age of thirteen, such user is not authorized to provide the UVU with personally identifiable information, and UVU will not use any such information in its database or other data collection activities. UVU appreciates cooperation with this federally mandated requirement. Users under the age of thirteen and their parents or guardians are cautioned that the collection of personally identifiable information volunteered by unauthorized children online or by e-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult until UVU becomes aware that the user is under the age of thirteen and such information may be subject to public access. 

## Utah Government Records Access and Management Act

As a public institution, and instrumentality of the State of Utah, UVU is subject to the Government Records Access and Management Act of the Utah Code, Section 63G-2-101 _et seq_., 1953, as may be amended (“GRAMA”).  This means that records, in all forms including email, provided to UVU are subject to public disclosure, unless the record is designated by law as confidential or not a public record. 

## Security

UVU implements appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect your information when you transmit it to us that ensure a level of security appropriate to the risks presented by the processing and the nature of the data to be protected. While UVU strives to protect your information, UVU cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information. 

## Related Policies

  * [Policies & Procedures 441 – Appropriate Use of Computing Facilities](https://policy.uvu.edu/getDisplayFile/56392daf65db23201153c236)
  * [Policies & Procedures 445 – Institutional Data Management and Access](https://policy.uvu.edu/getDisplayFile/56392e9e65db23201153c23a)
  * [Policies & Procedures 446 – Monitoring and Review of Employee Electronic Communications or Files](https://policy.uvu.edu/getDisplayFile/56392ed265db23201153c23b)

## Questions

If a user has questions about this Privacy Statement or believes that the user’s personal information has been released without consent, please send an e-mail to: [compliance@uvu.edu](mailto:compliance@uvu.edu?subject=).
